<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!-- $Revision: 1.31 $ -->

<sect1 id="usage-network" xreflabel="Network">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">Playing Files Over A Local Area Network</phrase>
  </title>

  <para lang="en">
    First of all, you'll need to have a working network. That means you'll 
    need a network switch with a patch cable to your PS2 and a patch cable 
    to your PC, Alternatively you can use a single crossover cable directly
    linking your PS2 to your PC. If you can't successfully ping your PS2 
    while you're running SMS, then you'll need to get that working first. 
    Once your network is working you can use either RadHostClient, or
    PS2Client-gui running on your PC to share your media directories. 
    RadHostClient is a little easier to use than ps2client-gui, and can 
    involve less running back and forth between the PC and PS2.
  </para>

  <sect2>
    <title>
      <phrase lang="en">Playing Network Video Files Using RadHostClient</phrase>
    </title>

    <para lang="en">
      Download and install RadHostClient from
      <ulink url="http://ps2dev.org/ps2/Tools/Misc_tools/Rad_Host_Client_1.4"/>.
      Run the application on your PC, and type in the IP address of your PS2
      in the text box at the top.  Drag folders into the list at the bottom.
      They will automatically be made available to the PS2.
    </para>

    <figure>
      <title>
        <phrase lang="en">
          RadHostClient in operation.
        </phrase>
      </title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/network-radhostclient.png" format="PNG"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject>
          <phrase>RadHostClient in operation.</phrase>
        </textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para lang="en">
      If you have not done so already, start SMS on your PS2, then
      <emphasis role="bold">On the PS2</emphasis> press
      <emphasis role="bold">START</emphasis> to bring up the SMS config
      menu, then select
      <emphasis role="bold">Nework settings...</emphasis>, then select
      <emphasis role="bold">start network interface now</emphasis>
      and press <emphasis role="bold">X</emphasis>.
    </para>
    <para lang="en">
      Within 10 seconds you should see a new device icon at the top of the
      SMS screen:
    </para>

    <figure>
      <title>
        <phrase lang="en">
          Screenshot of SMS with network support activated, (note additional 
          icon at top of screen).
        </phrase>
      </title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/usage-sms-networkactivated.png" 
            format="PNG"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject>
          <phrase>Screenshot of SMS with network support activated.</phrase>
        </textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para lang="en">
      Now press <emphasis role="bold">RIGHT</emphasis> to select the network 
      icon, and browse into the folders on your PC. When you press
      <emphasis role="bold">X</emphasis>, the PS2 will begin playback, and
      will stream the file from your PC across the network.
    </para>


    <figure>
      <title>
        <phrase lang="en">
          Browsing networked folder shared from remote PC.
        </phrase>
      </title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/usage-sms-networkbrowsing.png"
            format="PNG"/>
        </imageobject>
        <textobject>
          <phrase>Screenshot of SMS browsing networked folder shared from 
          remote PC.</phrase>
        </textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <warning>
      <para lang="en">
        Do not close RadHostClient while your PS2 is browsing files shared 
        via the client. This will cause both RadHostClient and the PS2 to 
        crash.
      </para>
      <para lang="en">
        If the PS2 crashes or restarts, you may need to restart RadHostClient.
      </para>
    </warning>
  </sect2>
  
  <sect2>
    <title>
      <phrase lang="en">Playing Network Video Files Using PS2Client-gui</phrase>
    </title>
    <para lang="en">
      <emphasis role="bold">On the PC</emphasis> download and install 
      ps2client-gui. Run the GUI, and select the directories of where your 
      videofiles are. If you have a base directory that contains all your 
      files, enter that directory. It doesn't matter if your files are in 
      subdirectories within this one, as you will be able to navigate them 
      in SMS. Once you click OK, it will make this available to your PS2.
    </para>
    <para lang="en">
      If you have not done so already, start SMS on your PS2, then
      <emphasis role="bold">On the PS2</emphasis> press
      <emphasis role="bold">START</emphasis> to bring up the SMS config
      menu, then select
      <emphasis role="bold">Nework settings...</emphasis>, then select
      <emphasis role="bold">start network interface now</emphasis>
      and press <emphasis role="bold">X</emphasis>.
    </para>

    <para lang="en">
      You should see a new device icon appear at the top of the screen. 
      If you don't see one after 20 secs, try stopping and restarting the 
      ps2client-gui program on your PC.  Once the icon appears (can take 
      around 15seconds), press <emphasis role="bold">RIGHT</emphasis> to 
      select it, then <emphasis role="bold">X</emphasis>. You should now be 
      able to navigate all folders beneath the one you shared.
    </para>

  </sect2>
</sect1>
