<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!-- $Revision: 1.31 $ -->


<sect1 id="faq-bootcddafs">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">
      <emphasis>I've made my CDDAFS CDR but my PS2 won't boot from it - It just
      sees it as an audio CD. What's wrong?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
    <phrase lang="pt">
      <emphasis>Criei o meu CD-R CDDAFS mas a minha PS2 não o inicia - apenas
      o vê como um CD de áudio. O que está errado?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
  </title>
  <para lang="en">
    CDXplorer does not create a CD-R which you can boot from. It just creates
    a disc that can be read once SMS is running. CDDAFS is not a method to
    launch SMS, it is a method to provide files to SMS once SMS is
    running. As far as I know there is no way to 'boot' SMS off a CD, DVD-R or
    any other removable media without a Mod-Chip. You always need either:
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    O CDXplorer não cria um CD-R a partir do qual se pode arrancar. Apenas
    cria um disco que pode ser lido quando o SMS já está a correr. CDDAFS não
    é um método de inicializar o SMS, é um método de fornecer os ficheiros ao
    SMS quando este já está a correr. Que eu saiba, não existe nenhum método
    para executar o SMS a partir de um CD, DVD-R ou qualquer outro tipo de 
    media amovivel sem ter um Mod-Chip. Precisa sempre de:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
    <listitem>
      <para lang="en">An exploit</para>
      <para lang="pt">Um exploit</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para lang="en">A mod chip</para>
      <para lang="pt">Ou um Mod-chip</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para lang="en">
    to run SMS first... and <emphasis>then</emphasis> you put in your CDDAFS
    disc, DVD-R or whatever. In many cases, <filename>SMS.ELF</filename>
    will be put on the memory card, then an exploit will be used to launch SMS
    from the memory card. Without an exploit or modchip there is no known way
    you can get your PS2 to run SMS. But if you find a way - let us know!
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    para executar o SMS primeiro... e <emphasis>depois</emphasis> coloca o seu
    disco CDDAFS, DVD-R, etc. Em muitos casos, o <filename>SMS.ELF</filename>
    será colocado no cartão de memória, depois será usado um exploit para 
    executar o SMS do cartão de memória. Sem um exploit ou sem um modchip não
    existe nenhum método conhecido para executar o SMS. Mas se descobrir uma
    maneira - diga-nos!!!
  </para>
</sect1>


<sect1 id="faq-ps2reality">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">
      <emphasis>How does SMS playback quality compare with
      <application>PS2Reality Media Player</application>?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
    <phrase lang="pt">
      <emphasis>Como é que a qualidade de vizualização do SMS se compara com 
      o <application>PS2Reality Media Player</application>?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
  </title>

  <para lang="en">
    We aren't currently attempting to compare or benchmark SMS against any
      other media players at the moment. The only goal is to make SMS as
    good as possible. If you'd like to do some detailed comparisons
    yourself, go ahead, we'd be interested in the results.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Não estamos a tentar comparar o SMS contra outros leitores de media de
    momento. O único objectivo é fazer o SMS o melhor possível. Se estiver
    interessado em fazer as suas próprias comparações, força nisso, seria
    interessante ver os resultados.
  </para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="faq-networkprobs01">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">
      <emphasis>I can't see my network files - what's wrong?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
    <phrase lang="pt">
      <emphasis>Não consigo ver os ficheiros na rede - o que se passa?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
  </title>

    <para lang="en">
      Check in the network settings menu (on SMS: Start->Network Settings), 
      and if you see it, press '<emphasis role="bold">start network 
      now</emphasis>'. Turning on 
      <emphasis role="bold">Autostart network</emphasis> will make SMS try 
      to access a client at startup. If you are still having problems,
      try restarting the client (e.g 
      <application>RadHostClient</application>) on your PC, and check the 
      instructions again.
    </para>
    <para lang="pt">
      Veja no menu de opções de rede (no SMS: Start->Network Settings),
      e se o vir, pressione '<emphasis role="bold">start network 
      now</emphasis>'. Ligar o 
      <emphasis role="bold">Autostart network</emphasis> fará com que o SMS
      tente ligar-se a um cliente ao iniciar. Se os problemas persistirem,
      tente reiniciar o cliente (e.g. <application>RadHostClient</application>) 
      no seu PC e releia as instruções.
    </para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="faq-exploit">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">
      <emphasis>What's an exploit? This sounds bad. Can I go to prison for 
      running an exploit?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
    <phrase lang="pt">
      <emphasis>O que é um 'exploit'? Cheira-me a esturro. Posso ir para a 
      prisão por usar um 'exploit'?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
  </title>

    <para lang="en">
      <trademark>Sony Computer Entertainment</trademark> disapprove of 
      exploits and mod-chips yet they continue to be sold across the world. 
      Legislation may vary in different countries, so you are advised to
      check local laws before installing an exploit or purchasing a 
      mod-chip.
    </para>
    <para lang="pt">
      A <trademark>Sony Computer Entertainment</trademark> desaprova os 
      exploits e mod-chips, mas estes continuam a ser vendidos em todo o mundo.
      A legislação pode variar de país para país, por isso é aconselhável que
      se informe das leis locaisantes de instalar o mod-chip ou exploit.
    </para>

</sect1>



<sect1 id="faq-independence" xreflabel="Independence Exploit">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">
      <emphasis>What is the <quote>Independence Exploit</quote> and how does
      it help me?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
    <phrase lang="pt">
      <emphasis>O que é o <quote>Independence Exploit</quote> e como é que me 
      ajuda?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
  </title>

  <para lang="en">
    The <emphasis role="bold">Independence Exploit</emphasis> is a software
    based exploit that allows a PS2 to run unencrypted and homebrew applications
    (such as SMS) from the memory card.  A description of what
    the exploit actually is can be found
    <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=PS2_Independence_Exploit&amp;oldid=33927710">
    here</ulink>.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    O <emphasis role="bold">Independence Exploit</emphasis> é um exploit 
    baseado em software que deixa a PS2 ler aplicações não encriptadas (tal
    como o SMS) a partir do cartão de memória.  A explicação mais concisa do
    que é o exploit pode ser encontrada 
    <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=PS2_Independence_Exploit&amp;oldid=33927710">
    aqui</ulink>.
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
    The Independence Exploit is one of the techniques that can be used to
    trick your PS2 into running SMS.  Normally your PS2 does not allow you
    to run unencrypted programs, and this protection is in place mainly
    to reduce the spread of copied games.  When it comes to legitimate
    open source projects like SMS, the protection only stands in the way of
    running  SMS.  When installed, the Independence Exploit allows the user to
    run  a specific application stored on the memory card.  Often the chosen
    application will be an ELF launching program (a file browser) which
    then allows further applications to be launched.  The Exploit itself
    is executed by inserting a chosen PS1 <quote>trigger disc</quote>,
    inserting a memory card with specially modified files on it, and
    then pressing reset.  Tutorial of how to get the correct specially
    modified files onto your memory card can be found
    <ulink url="http://www.exploitstation.com/index.php?page=faq">here</ulink>.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    O Independence Exploit é uma das técnicas que pode ser usada para enganar
    a PS2 para correr o SMS.  Normalmente a PS2 não permite que corra 
    programas não-encriptados, esta protecção existe principalmente para 
    reduzir a utilização de jogos copiados.  No que toca a projectos legitimos
    como o SMS, a protecção so impede que este seja executado. Quando instalado,
    O Independence Exploit deixa o utilizador correr uma aplicação especifica
    que esteja no cartão de memória.  Normamente a aplicação escolhida é um 
    programa de execução de ficheiros ELF (um navegador de ficheiros) que 
    depois permite correr outras aplicações. O Exploit em si é executado 
    introduzindo um  jogo de PS1 (escolhido), inserindo um cartão de memória
    com ficheiros especificamente modificados nele, e pressionando Reset. Um
    tutorial de como arranjar os ficheiros modificados para o cartão de 
    memória pode ser encontrado
    <ulink url="http://www.exploitstation.com/index.php?page=faq">aqui</ulink>.
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
    The recommended approach is to use the tutorial to install an ELF launching
    program and an FTP server.  Then you can use the FTP server to install
    as many other applications (ELF files) as you want.  It also then allows 
    you to make backups of all your saved games which is handy for those
    strange people who still use their PS2 to play games!
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    A aproximação recomendada é utilizar o tutorial para instalar um programa
    de execução de ficheiros ELF e um servidor de FTP. Depois pode utilizar o 
    servidor de FTP para instalar todas as aplicações (ficheiros ELF)que 
    desejar.  Isto permite também que faça cópias de segurança de todos os seus
    saves, que pode ser útil para aquelas pessoas estranhas que ainda usam a 
    PS2 para jogar jogos!
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
    The exploit is significant to SMS users since it is one of the cheapest
    ways of running SMS, requiring no additional hardware other than a
    PS2, a memory card, and an original PS1 game.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    O Exploit é importante para os utilizadores do SMS visto que é o método 
    mais barato de executar o SMS, não requerindo qualquer hardware extra para
    além da PS2, cartão de memória e um jogo original PS1.
  </para>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="faq-dhcp">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">
      <emphasis>I can't access SMS on my DHCP network.  SMS won't
      autoconfigure it's IP address.  What's wrong?
      </emphasis>
    </phrase>
    <phrase lang="pt">
      <emphasis>Não consigo aceder ao SMS na minha rede DHCP.  O SMS não 
      configura o seu IP automaticamente. O que se passa?
      </emphasis>
    </phrase>
  </title>
  <para lang="en">
    SMS will not automatically configure it's IP address from a DHCP (Dynamic
    Host Configuration Protocol) server, such as the DHCP server normally
    found running in wireless access points etc.  SMS requires a static
    (or manual) IP address, set in
    <filename>mc0:/SYS-CONF/IPCONFIG.DAT</filename>, (see
    <xref linkend="installation-configuration-ipconfig"/>).
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    O SMS não configura o seu endereço de IP numa rede de DHCP (Dynamic Host 
    Configuration Protocol), tal como os servidores DHCP normalmente 
    encontrados em access points wireless, etc.  SMS requere um endereço de IP
    estático (ou manual) configurado em
    <filename>mc0:/SYS-CONF/IPCONFIG.DAT</filename>, (veja
    <xref linkend="installation-configuration-ipconfig"/>).
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
    This does not mean that you need to disable DHCP and make your whole
    network run on static IP addresses.  All you need to do is check the
    configuration of the DHCP server, and manually set your PS2 IP address
    to be compatible.  Most DHCP servers will have a range of IP addresses
    that they will assign to DHCP clients (for example, my linksys WRT54G
    access point assigns IP addresses from 192.168.1.100 to 192.168.1.254)
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Isto não significa que tenha de desligar o DHCP e fazer com que toda a sua
    rede funcione com endereços estáticos.  Basta verificar a configuração do
    seu servidor de DHCP, e configurar o endereço de IP da PS2 manualmente para
    ser compatível.  A grande maioria dos servidores de DHCP tem um raio de
    endereços IP que irá atribuir aos clientes (por exemplo, a minha access
    point linksys WRT54G atribui endereços de IP de 192.168.1.100 a 
    192.168.1.254).
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
    As long as you set your PS2 IP address outside of this range (e.g.
    192.168.1.22), then SMS will run happily alongside your DHCP clients.
    You may need to adjust your DHCP settings by changing the start IP
    address if there is not already a range you can use.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Desde que atribua à PS2 um IP fora deste raio (e.g. 192.168.1.22), então
    o SMS correrá feliz junto com os seus clientes de DHCP. Pode ter de
    ajustar as suas definições de DHCP modificando o endereço de IP inicial se
    ainda não houver um raio que possa usar.
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
    Of course you need to make sure that the IP address you use is not
    used by any other nodes on your network (such as PCs, other PS2s, or
    the access point itself), and the PS2 must be on the same subnet (i.e.
    the first 3 numbers of the IP address must be the same as other nodes on
    your network).
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Tem de se certificar que o IP que está a usar não é usado por outros 
    aparelhos na sua rede local (tal como PC's, outras PS2's, ou a própria
    access point), e a PS2 tem de estar na mesma 'subnet' (i.e. os primeiros
    3 números do endereço de IP devem ser os mesmos que os outros aparelhos
    na sua rede local).
  </para>

  <tip>
    <para lang="en">
      If you are not sure whether you've got a DHCP server or not, go to
      a command prompt, and type <userinput>ipconfig /all</userinput>.  If
      you see a DHCP server listed with an IP address, then it means
      you <emphasis role="bold">have</emphasis> got a DHCP server running.
      You can usually access the configuration settings of access points
      by typing the access point IP address into a web browser.
    </para>
    <para lang="pt">
      Se não estiver certo se tem ou não um servidor de DHCP, vá ao command
      prompt e insira <userinput>ipconfig /all</userinput>.
      Se vir um servidor de DHCP listado com um endereço de IP, então isso
      significa que você <emphasis role="bold">tem</emphasis> um servidor de
      DHCP a correr. Pode normalmente aceder à configuração das access points
      inserindo o seu endereço de IP num navegador de internet.
    </para>
  </tip>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="faq-opticalout">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">
      <emphasis>Does the PS2 optical digital output (S/PDIF) work in SMS for
      AC3 passthrough?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
    <phrase lang="pt">
      <emphasis>A saída óptica digital (S/PDIF) da PS2 funciona no SMS para
      som AC3?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
  </title>
  <para lang="en">
    Yes, you can connect the PS2 output to an external audio processor
    via a fibre optic cable.  You can enable the output by selecting 
    <emphasis role="bold">SMS Menu -> Player settings</emphasis>. This has 
    been tested with a SoundBlaster PC sound card and 384kb/s ac3 streams.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    #Yes, you can connect the PS2 output to an external audio processor
    via a fibre optic cable.  This has been tested with a SoundBlaster
    PC sound card and 384kb/s ac3 streams.#
  </para>
  <note>
    <para lang="en">
      It is not possible to adjust the audio volume in this mode.
    </para>
    <para lang="pt">
      #It is not possible to adjust the audio volume in this mode.#
    </para>
  </note>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="faq-writeablemedia" xreflabel="Writeable Media Compatibility">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">
      <emphasis>What types of of writeable media
      (DVD-R/DVD+R/DVD+RW/DVD-RW/CDR/CDRW) will work with SMS?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
    <phrase lang="pt">
      <emphasis>#What types of of writeable media
      (DVD-R/DVD+R/DVD+RW/DVD-RW/CDR/CDRW) will work with SMS?#</emphasis>
    </phrase>
  </title>
  <para lang="en">
    Users have had success with all current types of writeable disc, but the 
    most popular in a
    <ulink url="http://www.ps2-scene.org/forums/showthread.php?t=44531">
    recent survey</ulink> was the DVD-R.  Please note that without a
    mod chip, the only way you can trick the PS2 into reading your
    home-burned discs, is either the <xref linkend="usage-cddafs"/> method
    or the <xref linkend="usage-dvdr"/> 'Dummy DVD Video Disc' method.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    #Users have had success with all current types of writeable disc, but the
    most popular in a
    <ulink url="http://www.ps2-scene.org/forums/showthread.php?t=44531">
    recent survey</ulink> was the DVD-R.  Please note that without a
    mod chip, the only way you can trick the PS2 into reading your
    home-burned discs, is either the <xref linkend="usage-cddafs"/> method
    or the <xref linkend="usage-dvdr"/> 'Dummy DVD Video Disc' method.#
  </para>

  <informaltable frame='none'>
  <tgroup cols='2'>
  <thead>
  <row>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">Format</para>
      <para lang="pt">#Format#</para>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">Working?</para>
      <para lang="pt">#Working?#</para>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">Comments</para>
      <para lang="pt">#Comments#</para>
    </entry>
  </row>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
  <row>
    <entry>CDR</entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">Yes</para>
      <para lang="pt">#Yes#</para>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">None</para>
      <para lang="pt">#None#</para>
    </entry>
  </row>
  <row>
    <entry>CDRW</entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">Yes</para>
      <para lang="pt">#Yes#</para>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">None</para>
      <para lang="pt">#None#</para>
    </entry>
  </row>
  <row>
    <entry>DVD-R</entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">Yes</para>
      <para lang="pt">#Yes#</para>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">None</para>
      <para lang="pt">#None#</para>
    </entry>
  </row>
  <row>
    <entry>DVD+R</entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">Yes</para>
      <para lang="pt">#Yes#</para>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">None</para>
      <para lang="pt">#None#</para>
    </entry>
  </row>
  <row>
    <entry>DVD-RW</entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">Yes</para>
      <para lang="pt">#Yes#</para>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">None</para>
      <para lang="pt">#None#</para>
    </entry>
  </row>
  <row>
    <entry>DVD+RW</entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">Yes</para>
      <para lang="pt">#Yes#</para>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <para lang="en">None</para>
      <para lang="pt">#None#</para>
    </entry>
  </row>
  </tbody>
  </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

</sect1>


