<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!-- $Revision: 1.31 $ -->


<sect1 id="faq-bootcddafs">
	<title>
	  <phrase lang="en">
		  <emphasis>I've made my CDDAFS CDR but my PS2 won't boot from it – It just
			sees it as an audio CD. What's wrong?</emphasis>
		</phrase>
	</title>
  <para lang="en">
    CDXplorer does not create a CD-R which you can boot from. It just creates
		a disc that can be read once SMS is running. CDDAFS is not a method to
		launch SMS, it is a method to provide files to SMS once SMS is
    running. As far as I know there is no way to 'boot' SMS off a CD, DVD-R or
		any other removable media without a Mod-Chip. You always need either:
	</para>
  <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
    <listitem>
      <para lang="en">An exploit</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para lang="en">A mod chip</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para lang="en">
    to run SMS first... and <emphasis>then</emphasis> you put in your CDDAFS
		disc, DVD-R or whatever. In many cases, <filename>SMS.ELF</filename>
		will be put on the memory card, then an exploit will be used to launch SMS
		from the memory card. Without an exploit or modchip there is no known way
		you can get your PS2 to run SMS. But if you find a way – let us know!
  </para>
</sect1>


<sect1 id="faq-ps2reality">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">
      <emphasis>How does SMS playback quality compare with
      <application>PS2Reality Media Player</application>?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
  </title>

    <para lang="en">
      We aren't currently attempting to compare or benchmark SMS against any
      other media players at the moment. The only goal is to make SMS as
      good as possible. If you'd like to do some detailed comparisons
      yourself, go ahead, we'd be interested in the results.
    </para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="faq-networkprobs01">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">
      <emphasis>I can't see my network files – what's wrong?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
  </title>

    <para lang="en">
      Check in the network settings menu (on SMS: Start->Network Settings), 
      and if you see it, press '<emphasis role="bold">start network 
      now</emphasis>'. Turning on 
      <emphasis role="bold">Autostart network</emphasis> will make SMS try 
      to access a client at startup. If you are still having problems,
      try restarting the client (e.g 
      <application>RadHostClient</application>) on your PC, and check the 
      instructions again.
    </para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="faq-exploit">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">
      <emphasis>What's an exploit? This sounds bad. Can I go to prison for 
      running an exploit?</emphasis>
    </phrase>
  </title>

    <para lang="en">
      <trademark>Sony Computer Entertainment</trademark> disapprove of 
      exploits and mod-chips yet they continue to be sold across the world. 
      A recent court case in Australia 
      <ulink url="http://www.afterdawn.com/news/archive/6906.cfm"/> ruled 
      that the use of mod-chips for legal purposes outweighed the illegal 
      ones.  
    </para>
    <para lang="en">
      However, this says nothing for copyright infringement.
      If you intend to use a mod-chip or exploit to run pirate copies of
      games this is copyright infringement and is illegal.
    </para>
    <para lang="en">
      If you intend to copy or 'rip' DVD movies which you do not own to any
      other format then this is also illegal.
      Downloading copyrighted movies ripped by other people is also illegal.
    </para>

</sect1>



<sect1 id="faq-independence" xreflabel="Independence Exploit">
  <title>
	  <phrase lang="en">
	    <emphasis>What is the <quote>Independence Exploit</quote> and how does
			it help me?</emphasis>
	  </phrase>
  </title>

  <para lang="en">
    The <emphasis role="bold">Independence Exploit</emphasis> is a software
    based exploit that allows a PS2 to run unencrypted and homebrew applications
    (such as SMS) from the memory card.  The most concise description of what
    the exploit actually is can be found
		<ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=PS2_Independence_Exploit&amp;oldid=33927710">
		here</ulink>.
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
	  The Independence Exploit is one of the techniques that can be used to
		trick your PS2 into running SMS.  Normally your PS2 does not allow you
		to run unencrypted programs, and this protection is in place mainly
		to reduce the spread of copied games.  When it comes to legitimate
		open source projects like SMS, the protection only stands in the way of
		running	SMS.  When installed, the Independence Exploit allows the user to 
    run	a specific application stored on the memory card.  Often the chosen
		application will be an ELF launching program (a file browser) which
		then allows further applications to be launched.  The Exploit itself
		is executed by inserting a chosen PS1 <quote>trigger disc</quote>,
		inserting a memory card with specially modified files on it, and
		then pressing reset.  Tutorial of how to get the correct specially
		modified files onto your memory card can be found
		<ulink url="http://www.exploitstation.com/index.php?page=faq">here</ulink>.
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
    The recommended approach is to use the tutorial to install an ELF launching
    program and an FTP server.  Then you can use the FTP server to install
    as many other applications (ELF files) as you want.  It also then allows 
		you to make backups of all your saved games which is handy for those
		strange people who still use their PS2 to play games!
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
    The exploit is significant to SMS users since it is one of the cheapest
    ways of running SMS, requiring no additional hardware other than a
    PS2, a memory card, and an original PS1 game.
  </para>
</sect1>