<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!-- $Revision: 1.26 $ -->

<para lang="en">
  Simple Media System (<application>SMS</application>) is a result the
  original author's (Eugene Plotnikov's) curiosity about Sony's Playstation2,
  MIPS, DivX and MP3.
  His original goal was to create a simple DivX player able to play good
  resolution movies at good frame rate on an unmodded PS2 without any extra
  equipment such as HDD and network adapter.
</para>

<para lang="en">
  Why create a complete "system"? Just because having only a player program
  is not enough. Since the PS2 conventionally ignores "illegal" disks, he
  took the idea of Drakonite with his UMCDR and developed his own "UMCDR".
  (called CDDAFS). It just stores data on a CD audio disk format, which can
  be read on (hopefully) any PS2.
</para>

<para lang="en">
  This is the first component of SMS. The second component is a PC program
  that makes cue/bin files in order to burn such a disk. And, finally, comes
  a player program itself. This system is not complete yet, but it can play
  DivX movies with sound at good frame rate already. Player's base is a
  famous ffmpeg project. EEUG took just some parts of it (DivX 5XX and MP3)
  and made some modifications specific to PS2 hardware. It has been tested
  with many DivX/XviD movies with different screen resolutions and encoding
  methods and it seems to be working.
</para>

<para lang="en">
  Since the initial concept, the SMS project has now grown to include
  support for network files, USB drives, hard disc drives. It now also allows
  subtitles to be displayed, and contains a fully functional MP3 player.
  All the software is now available in the subversion (SVN) repository at
  ps2dev.org. It has been made available in the hope that it will be
  interesting for PS2 enthusiasts who use it as a base for their own
  development.
</para>

<para lang="en">
  This document provides comprehensive installation and usage instructions.
  Currently it is written/maintained in DocBook XML format, and processed
  for output in a variety of formats including single HTML and HTML pages
  grouped into sections.  Later it will (hopefully) be distributed in PDF
  format as well.
</para>
