<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>

  <para lang="en">
    So, now that you've got SMS installed on your PS2
    (see <xref linkend="installation"/>), how do you get it play movies?  This
    chapter explains all you need to know.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Agora que o SMS j est instalado na PS2
    (veja <xref linkend="installation"/>), como ver os filmes?  Este
    explica tudo o que voc precisa de saber.
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
    To run SMS you first need to run your exploit or start up your PS2 with
    the modchip installed.  Then use the appropriate technique to start the
    SMS program. If you're using the
    <xref linkend="faq-independence"/>
    insert your (legitimate) PS1 trigger disc, and press reset. This will boot
    your chosen launcher application, where you can select which actual ELF
    you want to run.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Para correr o SMS primeiro voc precisa de correr o 'exploit' ou ligar a 
    PS2 se tiver modchip instalado.  Depois tem de utilizar a tcnica 
    apropriada para ligar o SMS.  Se estiver a usar o
    <xref linkend="faq-independence"/>
    insira o seu CD de PS1 (original), e pressione reset. Isto executar
    a aplicao de gesto ('LaunchElf por exemplo'), onde puder escolher qual o 
    ELF que quer executar.
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
    Next, if you're using LaunchELF as your boot application, you can run SMS
    by navigating to SMS.ELF and pressing O. You may want to assign a shortcut
    button to it so it is easier to load next time.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    De seguida, se estiver a usar o LaunchELF como aplicao inicial, pode
    corre o SMS bastando para isso navegar ate ao ficheiro SMS.ELF e 
    pressionar O.  Talvez queira adicionar um buto de atalho para o SMS para 
    ser mais fcil de carregar na prxima vez.
  </para>

  <tip>
    <para lang="en">
      If you use SMS regularly, you may want to assign it as the 'default'
      option in LauchELF, so that it starts automatically, after a short
      delay.
    </para>
    <para lang="pt">
      Se voc usa o SMS regularmente, talvez queira adicion-lo como a opo
      'default' no LauchELF, para que ele seja executado automticamente, 
      passado pouco tempo.
    </para>
  </tip>

  <para lang="en">
    Once you've got SMS running, you should see the nice SMS graphical
    interface on your TV set. From this point onwards, all the instructions
    are the same, whichever Exploit/Modchip you are using.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Assim que tiver o SMS a correr, dever ver a bela 'interface' do SMS
    no seu televisor. Daqui para a frente, todas as instrues
    so as mesmas, qualquer que seja o 'exploit'/modchip que estiver a usar.
  </para>

  <figure>
    <title>
       <phrase lang="en">
         Screenshot of SMS main GUI. (files you see are a directory listing
         of the current CD in the drive - the independence trigger disc in
         this case).
      </phrase>
      <phrase lang="pt">
        Screenshot do interface do SMS. (os ficheiros que voc v so os
        ficheiros presentes no CD que se encontra na PS2 - o disco de
        arranque do 'exploit independence' neste caso).
      </phrase>
    </title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="../images/usage-sms-maingui.png" format="PNG"/>
      </imageobject>
      <textobject lang="en">
        <phrase>SMS Main GUI</phrase>
      </textobject>
      <textobject lang="pt">
        <phrase>GUI principal do SMS</phrase>
      </textobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

  <para lang="en">
    This is the screen where you will access most features from. The files
    can be navigated using up/down/left right on controller 1 or 2, and you
    can play them by pressing <emphasis role="bold">X</emphasis>.
    A special configuration menu is accessed by
    pressing <emphasis role="bold">start</emphasis>.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Este  o ecr de onde poder aceder a mais opes. Pode navegar pelos
    ficheiros usando as teclas cima/baixo/esq./dir. nos controladores 1 ou 2,
    e poder corre-los pressionando <emphasis role="bold">X</emphasis>.
    Um menu de configurao pode ser acedido
    pressionando <emphasis role="bold">start</emphasis>.
  </para>
