<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<!-- $Revision: 1.26 $ -->

<sect1 id="sms-installation-requirements">
  <title>
    <phrase lang="en">Requirements</phrase>
    <phrase lang="el">#Requirements#</phrase>
    <phrase lang="es">#Requirements#</phrase>
    <phrase lang="pt">Requerimentos</phrase>
  </title>
  
  <para lang="en">
    To install SMS on your Playstation 2 you will need the following:
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Para instalar o SMS na sua PlayStation 2 necessita do seguinte:
  </para>

  <itemizedlist mark='number'>
    <listitem>
      <para lang="en">
        A PS2 (chubby version if you'll be using the independence exploit)
      </para>
      <para lang="el">
        #A PS2 (chubby version if you'll be using the independence exploit)#
      </para>
      <para lang="es">
        #A PS2 (chubby version if you'll be using the independence exploit)#
      </para>
      <para lang="pt">
        Uma PS2 (versão 'grande' se estiver a usar o 'independence exploit')
      </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para lang="en">
        Working exploit or modchip which allows you to run ELF files
      </para>
      <para lang="el">
        #Working exploit or modchip which allows you to run ELF files#
      </para>
      <para lang="es">
        #Working exploit or modchip which allows you to run ELF files#
      </para>
      <para lang="pt">
        Exploit ou Modchip que lhe permitam correr ficheiros ELF
      </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para lang="en">
        (optional but recommended) Official PS2 Network Adaptor kit - for
        playing your PC's movie collection via a local area network.
      </para>
      <para lang="el">
        #(optional but recommended) Official PS2 Network Adaptor kit - for
        playing your PC's movie collection via a local area network.#
      </para>
      <para lang="es">
        #(optional but recommended) Official PS2 Network Adaptor kit - for
        playing your PC's movie collection via a local area network.#
      </para>
      <para lang="pt">
        (opcional mas recomendado) Adaptador de Rede para PS2 - para 
        vizualizar os seus filmes através da rede.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>


  <important>
    <para lang="en">
      To use SMS on your
      Playstation, you will need to already have a working method to run
      arbitrary ELF files from your PS2 memory card.  Normal PS2s can't do
      this.  SMS is not an exploit to run ELF files, it needs an exploit or
      modchip to run.   You can't just burn the SMS.ELF file to CD as the PS2
      copy protection  system will stop you from running it.  Please also note
      that the CDXplorer CD-R method is not a method of starting SMS either.
      Rather it is a way of supplying media files to SMS once SMS is already
      running.
    </para>
    <para lang="pt">
      Para utilizar o SMS na sua Playstation necessitará de ter um método para
      correr ficheiros ELF a partir do seu Cartão de Memória.  PS2 normais
      não conseguem fazer isto.  O SMS não é um meio para correr ficheiros 
      ELF, ele necessita de um exploit ou de um modchip para correr.  Não
      pode simplesmente gravar o SMS.ELF para um CD visto que o sistema de
      protecção anti-cópia da PS2 o impedirá de ler.  Por favor tenha também 
      em atenção que o método do CDXplorer também não servirá para correr o 
      SMS.  É apenas um método de fornecer ficheiros de media ao SMS assim que
      o SMS já esteja a correr.
    </para>
  </important>

  <para lang="en">
    You will need one of the following (some of which are free):
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Precisará de um dos seguintes (alguns são grátis):
  </para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para lang="en">
        A working exploit in place (such as the independence exploit
        <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PS2_Independence_Exploit"/>
        <ulink url="http://www.exploitstation.com/index.php?page=faq"/>)
        AND a working ELF launching program (such as
        LaunchELF), AND a PSX (playstation 1) trigger disc.
      </para>
      <para lang="pt">
        Um exploit a funcionar (tal como o independence exploit
        <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PS2_Independence_Exploit"/>
        <ulink url="http://www.exploitstation.com/index.php?page=faq"/>)
        E ainda um programa para executar ficheiros ELF (tal como o LaunchELF),
        E um disco de PSX (playstation 1) original.
      </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem override='none'>
      <para lang="en">OR</para>
      <para lang="pt">OU</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para lang="en">
        A mod chip in your PS2 that lets you run arbitrary ELF files.
      </para>
      <para lang="pt">
        Um modchip na sua PS2 que o deixe correr ficheiros ELF.
      </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem override='none'>
      <para lang="en">OR</para>
      <para lang="pt">OU</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para lang="en">
        PS2 linux kit and some way of using this to launch arbitrary ELF
        files (try <ulink url="http://playstation2-linux.com/projects/haven/">
        here</ulink>).
      </para>
      <para lang="pt">
        O kit de Linux para PS2 e uma maneira de o utilizar para executar 
        ficheiros ELF (tente 
        <ulink url="http://playstation2-linux.com/projects/haven/">
        aqui</ulink>).
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para lang="en">
    If you do not have any of the the above three items, you will not be able
    to run SMS. You need to get one of them <emphasis>before</emphasis>
    going any further with this installation guide.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Se não tiver nenhum dos items acima descritos não poderá correr o SMS. 
    Necessita de ter um deles <emphasis>antes</emphasis> de ir mais longe no
    guia da instalação.
  </para>

  <para lang="en">
    Assuming you do, please read on to the next section for how to install
    SMS onto your PS2 memory card.
  </para>
  <para lang="pt">
    Assumindo que tem um destes métodos, leia a próxima secção para instalar o
    SMS no Cartão de Memória da sua PS2.
  </para>

</sect1>